<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-29T03:53:43-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A (software) engineering notebook</title><subtitle>Watch another software engineer fall into a deep despair trying to understand how sand thinks better than me</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Another Hello world</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/12/28/Birth-of-Life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Another Hello world" /><published>2023-12-28T21:09:56-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-28T21:09:56-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/12/28/Birth-of-Life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2023/12/28/Birth-of-Life.html">&lt;p&gt;For my highschool’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Lead_the_Way&quot;&gt;Project Lead The Way Engineering course&lt;/a&gt;, my engineering notebook was a core part of the class. Spending time drawing 1 and 2 point perspective drawings, the notes earlier in the semester was something I could always look back upon. That should’ve been when I learned taking notes was important…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told myself during college that notebooks were stupid. All my slides and lectures were online, why would I waste money on a notebook I’d never look backupon. One of my many realizations of adulthood is that winging it really only gets you so far. There have been many incidents where I had learned some technical concept for it to be forgotten later. Advent of Code 2023 really humbled my knowledge of data structure and algorithims to the point where I had to re-lookup what breadth-first-search was. I’d classify my current reality as being a really junior software engineer. I’m still learning how to fully utilize my tools and industry standards. Every day I’m still learning concepts which I know I will eventually need something to look back upon. So in the spirit of starting something new&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-golang&quot; data-lang=&quot;golang&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;package&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Hello&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Blog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">For my highschool’s Project Lead The Way Engineering course, my engineering notebook was a core part of the class. Spending time drawing 1 and 2 point perspective drawings, the notes earlier in the semester was something I could always look back upon. That should’ve been when I learned taking notes was important… I told myself during college that notebooks were stupid. All my slides and lectures were online, why would I waste money on a notebook I’d never look backupon. One of my many realizations of adulthood is that winging it really only gets you so far. There have been many incidents where I had learned some technical concept for it to be forgotten later. Advent of Code 2023 really humbled my knowledge of data structure and algorithims to the point where I had to re-lookup what breadth-first-search was. I’d classify my current reality as being a really junior software engineer. I’m still learning how to fully utilize my tools and industry standards. Every day I’m still learning concepts which I know I will eventually need something to look back upon. So in the spirit of starting something new</summary></entry></feed>